# U. K. C. P. MAHINDA

No. 397 D. Sandun Uyana,

Hokandara North, Hokandara. - Sri Lanka.

Phone: Mobile : +94 703550265

Residence : +94 718089354

E-mail : mahinda.udawatta@gmail.com



#### Vision

Fulfill organizational and personal objectives through improved quality in planning, operationalization, supervision and ensuring productivity of workforce.

### Mission

Enhance personal skills through education, training, exposure and experience for better understanding of workplace and life dynamics to be a leader and a mentor in versatile work platforms to identify talents of people and align them for improved productivity and quality.

# **Career Objective**

To contribute for high quality productions in any industry through sound professional experience in the production management field while committing towards continuous self-improvement and innovations in the industry.

#### **Personal Characteristics**

- Fast Learner-possess high level ability to learn work related details on technical and operational aspects in a short period of time and enthusiastic on learning new areas
- Versatile Can handle multiple tasks to fulfill work related matters
- Adaptable Get used situations and quickly fit in Analytical Analyze work situations quickly and use them for future planning
- Rational decision maker Takes decisions based on a rationale backed by analysis
- Skill picker Identifies workforce SWOT quickly and put right people into right places and provide them with relevant assistance for capacity building
- Soft and Sharp Very natural and easy going with people but sharp to keep them on track

## **Professional Qualifications**

- Diploma in Production Management at Indian institute of Management & Technology.
- Green Belt Award for six Sigma at NIBM
- Diploma in Information & Communication Technology at YASASS Computer Training Institute, Sri Lanka.
- Diploma in English at London Business School
- Certificate Course in Hotel Management at Ceylon Hotel School Passed

# **Special Awards and Achievements**

- Best Kaizen Award at 4th National Convention in 2003
- Quality Circle Award at 4th National Convention in 2003
- Continuous Improvement Award in 2004 by Uni Dil Packaging Ltd.
- Award for Productivity Improvement through Employee Counseling in 2005 by Uni Dil Packaging

#### **Short Term Courses Attended**

- 5S Practices and Implementation
- Training Programme on Living beyond Limits Conducted by Sensei
- Training Programme on Neuron Linguistic Conducted by sensei
- Training Programme on Service Excellence Conducted by sensei
- Training Programme on Refocus and Re-invent and Re profits Conducted by sensei
- Training Programme on Synergetic Leadership Conducted by Sensei
- Participated workshop on "Internal Auditing ISO 9001:2000" at SLSI
- Participated in work shop on "Seven Habits" conducted by Mr. Lalith Fernando
- Participated Training Programme on "Customer service Excellence" conducted by Mr.
   Dammika Kalupage
- Attended several seminars in the field of HR

### **Educational Qualifications**

- ✓ GCE A/L (1986) in Science stream with a credit an 3 passes
- ✓ GCE O/L (1982) with 2 Distinctions and 6 Credits

# **Skills & Capabilities**

- Printing and manufacturing of corrugate boards, cartons & metal cans.
- Printing and manufacturing of woven label fabric and heat transfer labels.
- Printing and manufacturing of offset boards and thermal labels.
- Workforce Management
- Grievance handling
- Workforce planning
- Material and stock management
- Sense of different machine debugging
- Versatility with different machines and production patterns

# **Main Tasks and Responsibilities**

- Responsibility of overall effective operation of production department
- Actively Participated Quality Circle and productivity improvements
- Monitoring and evaluating departmental production plans
- Monitor that the allocation of resources is done in the most cost-effective manner,
- to achieve company goals
- Overlook proper maintenance work is carried out on machinery and equipment
- Planned preventive maintenance that would enhance productivity
- Monitoring critical factors
- Co-ordinate between shifts and other departments to optimizing manufacturing process
- Responsible for control of activities to eliminate waste
- Generated reports and information
- Training and Development
- Counseling of employees
- Welfare matters such as Canteen management, organizing get-togethers, excursion and other recreation and other events etc.
- Responsible for all type of contract workers Performance Management. A good practitioner in 5'S' (Secretary Steering committee)
- Internal Auditor (ISO)

# **Working Experience**

•	Weetraa Holdings Pvt Ltd (corrugated cartons) Factory Manager.	2020-Jan- up to date
•	Fine Pack Care Industry. (corrugated cartons)  Marketing & Product Development Manager	2018-Jan to 2020-Jan.
•	International Trimmings & Labels Lanka Pvt Ltd. Asst. Manager Production.	2014-Feb to 2017 Dec
•	Tunip Lanka Pvt Ltd. (corrugated cartons) Plant Manager	2013-Feb-2014-Feb
•	Sunshine Packaging Ltd. (Metal cans) Manager. Printing & Quality	2011 to 2013
•	<b>Express International Company (Egypt) (corrugated cartons)</b> Production Manager.	2010-2011
•	Nisol Corrugated Cartons Ltd (corrugated cartons) Production Manager	2007 to 2009.
•	Uni-dil Packaging Ltd (corrugated cartons) Assistant Production Manager	1998 to 2007
•	Eastern Pak (Dammam - K S A) (corrugated carton) Production Foreman	1994 to 1998
•	Nisol Corrugated Cartons Ltd (corrugated cartons) Production Supervisor	1989 to 1994

### **Personal Details**

➤ Date of Birth : 1966.06.07
 ➤ N.L.C No : 661591528 V
 ➤ Nationality : Sri Lankan
 ➤ Gender : Male.
 ➤ Civil Status : Married

### **Non-related Referees:**

#### Mr. Najith Paranagama

Director Operations
International Trimmings & Labels Lanka (Pvt) Ltd
No.72 D. Hokandara Road,
Thalawathugoda.

Mobile: 0094 773072082

## Dr. Deepal N Perera

Principal Management Consultant.
DSMS Management Consultant Ent.
236," Dilani", Kirindivita Rd.
Ganemulla, Srilanka

Mobile: 0094 77222223

I declare that particulars furnished above are true and accurate to the best of my knowledge. assure you that I would commit myself for the improvement of the printing industry at your organization.

Yours truly,

